A Guide to the Executive Papers of Governor Edmund Randolph, 1786-1788
Library of Virginia
Additional significant documents include the following: the oath of fidelity to Governor Randolph by John Harvie (1786 Dec. 1); an oath of fidelity to Bolling Starke as Privy Councilor (1786 Dec. 4); a proclamation by the governor outlawing certain escaped prisoners (1786 Dec. 23); a letter from Samuel Huntingdon, Governor of Connecticut, appointing commissioners to assemble in Convention in Philadelphia (1786 Dec. 23); a letter from John Blair regarding his appointment as a member of the committee to meet in Philadelphia in May (1786 Dec. 25); a letter from David Ross concerning his claim for the use of his property at Point of Fork (1787 Jan. 30); a proclamation by the Governor authorizing surveys to be made on the lands allotted to the Virginia Line on Continental Establishment (1787 Jan. 25); a letter from Piomingo, Chief of the Chickasaw Nation, regarding the Treaty at Kieve (1787 Feb. 15); a proclamation concerning the seizure of Spanish property by George Rogers Clark (1787 Feb. 28); the bond of John Pendleton as Auditor of Public Accounts (1787 March 1); a proclamation offering a reward for the capture of Presley Hunt & Ephraim Andrews, escaped prisoners (1787 March 2); a letter from Monsieur Oster, French Consul, applying for an order to prevent the departure of M.S. Deschamps to France (1787 April 1); a letter from William Smith enclosing a list of field officers in the Northampton County militia (1787 April 4); a letter from George Mason regarding payment as a delegate of the Constitutional Convention (1787 April 23); a proclamation for the reward & capture of Irby Philips (1787 April 28); a list of tobacco saved from Byrd Warehouse (1787 June 6); a letter from Governor Randolph to the lieutenant governor regarding a warrant for the expense of transporting his family to Philadelphia (1787 June 6); a letter from Governor Randolph enclosing George Wythe's resignation (1787 June 21); a letter from George Mason concerning the resignation of George Wythe as a delegate to the Convention (1787 June 30); a letter from the Governor providing his account for the Constitutional Convention (1787 July 12); an agreement between David Ross & Col. Meriwether for Point of Fork including a valuation of the 24 acres of land (1787 Aug. 8); a letter from Randolph forwarding a copy of the National Constitution and expressing his opposition to it (1787 Sept. 18); a letter from George Rogers Clark regarding the settlement of western accounts (1787 Oct. 8); a letter from Samuel Johnston, Governor of North Carolina, regarding an act to hold a Convention in Virginia in June (1788 Jan. 22); the proceedings of the Massachusetts Constitutional Convention to ratify the U.S. Constitution (1788 Feb. 6); the proceedings of the Georgia Constitutional Convention (1788 Feb. 5); a letter from John Sevier, Governor of Franklin, regarding the dispute between the state of Franklin & North Carolina (1788 March 27); a letter from Benjamin Franklin regarding the sanity of Mr. Elam (1788 May 12); a proclamation regarding the act establishing district courts as unconstitutional (1788 May 14); a letter from William Heth & David Henley, Commissioners of the Western Territory, enclosing their report on the claims of Virginia for the territory ceded to Congress (1788 May 15); a circular from Thomas Pinckney, Governor of South Carolina, regarding the ratification of the Constitution by a Convention in South Carolina (1788 May 24); a letter from Andrew Limonin regarding the bust of the Marquis de Lafayette (1788 Nov. 11); and a letter from the Council of State regarding Governor Randolph's departure from office (1788 Nov. 13).
Arrangement
Material arranged chronologically with undated items arranged at the end of each year.
Contents List
- Executive Papers of Governor Edmund Randolph
- 1786
  - December
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 21-30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1787
  - January
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 11-20 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 21-30 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - February
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 12-19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 21-28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - March
    - 1-10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 12-19 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 21-31 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - April
    - 1-10 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 11-20 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 21-25 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 26-30 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - May
    - 1-9 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 11-19 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 21-31 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - June
    - 1-9 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 11-20 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 21-30 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - July
    - 2-10 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 11-19 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 21-31 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - August
    - 1-10 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 11-19 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 20-30 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - September
    - 1-13 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 15-20 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 22-29 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - October
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 11-19 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 21-31 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Report on Naval Offices (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - November
    - 2-10 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 11-19 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 21-30 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - December
    - 1-10 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - 11-20 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - 21-31 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Board of Treasury (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Land Grants (Box 4, Folder 13)
- 1788
  - January
    - 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 12-17 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 22-31 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - February
    - 1-9 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 11-20 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 21-29 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - March
    - 2-10 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 11-20 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 21-31 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - April
    - 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 11-20 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 21-30 (31) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - May
    - 1-10 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - 12-20 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - 22-31 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - June
    - 2-10 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 11-20 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - 21-30 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - July
    - 2-10 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 11-20 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - 21-31 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - August
    - 1-9 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - 11-20 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - 21-26 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - September
    - 1-10 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - 11-20 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - 21-30 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - October
    - 1-10 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - 11-20 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - 21-31 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - November
    - 1-13 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Land Grants (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Dunscomb, Andrew - 1786-1788 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Point of Fork Arsenal - 1786-1787 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Oversized (Clamshell Box)
  - 1786
    - Dec. 11 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Dec. 20 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1787
    - Jan. 10 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - March 30 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - April 10 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - April 17 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - April 19 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - April 30 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - May 1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - May 6 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - May 27 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - June 20 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - July 5 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Nov. 19 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Dec. 21 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Board of Treasury (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - 1788
    - Feb. 4 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Feb. 5 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - March 13 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - March 13 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - April 3 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - April 3 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - April 14 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - April 15 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - April 17 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - May 3 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - May 8 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - May 12 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - May 13 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - May 15 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - May 15 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - May 17 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - May 17 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - May 19 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - May 26 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - June 2 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - June 12 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - June 16 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - June 21 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - July 7 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - July 14 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - July 15 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - July 15 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - July 30 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Aug. 19 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Aug. 26 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Sept. 12 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Oct. 8 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Oct. 30 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Point of Fork Arsenal
    - Pay Roll of Artificers, 1787 April-June (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Quarterly Return of Clothing, 1787 March (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Return of Provisions, 1787 Jan.-March
- Oversized (Newspaper Box)
  - 1787
    - Jan. 12 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - April 2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - May 19 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - June 5 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Oct. 16 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Oct. 21 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Nov. 3 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 1788
    - Jan. 12 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - April 8 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - June 12 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - July 28 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Aug. 23 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Sept. 30 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Oct. 4 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Oct. 31 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Point of Fork Arsenal
    - Quarterly Return of Ordnance & Military Stores, 1787 April-June (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Quarterly Return of Quarter Master Stores, 1787 Jan.-March (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Quarterlty Return of Quarter Master Stores, 1787 April-June (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Quarterly Summary Account of Clothing 1787 April-June (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Return of Military Stores, 1787 April-June (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Return of Ordnance & Military Stores 1787 Jan.-March (Box 9, Folder 21)